freepsdflyer.com 2014-05-10

# Privacy Policy - FreePSDFlyer

### Privacy Policy of www.freepsdflyer.com

This application collects some Personal Data from its Users.

* * *

### Policy summary

* * *

##### Personal data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

#### Analytics

**Google Analytics**  
Personal Data: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data

#### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

**Facebook Like button and social widgets, Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets, Twitter Tweet button and social widgets and Google+ +1 button and social widgets**  
Personal Data: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data

#### Email contact

**Contact form**  
Personal Data: First Name, Last Name and Email

#### RSS feed management

**Feedburner**  
Personal Data: Browsing and usage Data and Cookie

#### Advertising

**Google Adsense**  
Personal Data: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data

* * *

### Contact information

**Data owner**  
designsonar media, help(a)freepsdflyer.com

* * *

### Full policy

* * *

#### Data Processing Ownership

designsonar media,  
help(a)freepsdflyer.com

* * *

#### Types of Data collected

Among the Data that this Application may collect there are: Cookie, Browsing and usage Data, First Name, Last Name and Email.  
Other Personal Data collected may be highlighted by other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text, in the moment when the Data collection happens.  
The Personal Data may be freely inserted by the User or the Data Subject, or collected automatically when using the Application.  
Any use of Cookies by the Application or the owners of third party services used by the Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify the User and remember his/her preferences for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data, in particular Navigation Data, by deactivating the Application’s Cookies may make it impossible to surf or for the Application to provide its services.  
The Personal Data collected may regard both the User and third parties whose data the User provides.  
The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through the Application and declares that (s)he has the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Owner of all responsibility towards third parties.

* * *

#### Mode and place of processing the Data obtained

**Method of Processing**  
The Data Controller processes the Data of the Interested Parties and Users in a lawful and proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction of the Data. Processing is carried out using computers and / or telematic means, with organizational methods and logics strictly related to the stated purposes.  
In addition to the owner, in some cases, access to the Data may be available to external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies). The updated list of Managers may be requested from the Owner at any time.

**Place**  
The Data are processed at the headquarters of the Data Controller, unless stated otherwise in the rest of this document.

**Conservation Time**  
The Data are kept for the time necessary to perform the service requested by the User, and the User can always ask for their suspension or removal.

* * *

#### The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User or the Data Subject are collected for the following purposes: Analytics, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Email contact, RSS feed management and Advertising.  
The kinds of Personal Data used for each purpose are given in the specific sections of this document.  
The use of Data for additional purposes by the Owner may in some cases, and for legal purposes, require specific consent by the User or the Data Subject.

* * *

#### Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data and the services provided by third parties

Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

##### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

**Google Analytics (Google)**

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine Application use, to prepare reports on an Application’s activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.  
Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

##### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the Application’s pages.  
The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

**Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook)**  
The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

**Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)**  
The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://about.pinterest.com/terms/)

**Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter)**  
The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

**Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google)**  
The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

##### Email contact

**Contact form (This Application)**  
By filling in the Contact form with his/her Data, the User authorizes the Application to use these details to reply to requests for information, quotes or any other kind of request as indicated by the form’s header.  
Personal data collected: First Name, Last Name and Email.

##### RSS feed management

These services allow the Application to manage RSS feeds and the distribution of their content. Depending on the characteristics of the service used, these services may be used to insert ads within the content and to gather statistics data from them.

**Feedburner (Google)**  
Feedburner is a service to manage RSS feeds provided by Google Inc. It allows the collection of statistics on what content is consulted and to insert ads in it.

Personal data collected: Browsing and usage Data and Cookie.  
Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

##### Advertising

These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on the Application, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

**Google Adsense (Google)**  
Google Adsense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks Application use and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.

Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en)

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://google.com/privacy/ads/)

* * *

#### Additional information about data processing

**Legal Protection**  
The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner of the Application in court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from its improper use or that of related services by the User.

**Additional Information**  
Specific information may be shown on the pages of the Site concerning particular services or the processing of Data provided by the User or by the Data Subject.

**Maintenance**  
The User’s Personal Data may be further used in ways and for purposes required for Application maintenance.

**System Logs**  
For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services it uses may collect system logs, i.e., files that record interaction – including navigation. They may also contain personal data, such as IP addresses.

**Information not contained in this policy**  
More information on processing Personal Information may be requested from the Owner at any time.

**The Rights of Data Subjects**  
Those persons to whom the Data refer have the right, at any time, to know whether their data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Owner of the Processing System.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
The Application reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page, and by ensuring analogous protection of the Personal Information in all cases. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.

**Information about this privacy policy**  
The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on the Iubenda’s servers.

* * *

#### Definitions and legal references

**Personal information or Data**  
Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

**Browsing and usage Data**  
Information collected automatically from the Site, including the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the users who connect to the site, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the visitor, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page) and the details about the path followed within the site with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the operating system and the user’s IT environment.

**User**  
Means the individual user of the Application’s services or products.

**Data Subject**  
The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refer.

**Data Processor**  
The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other organization, association or organization designated by the Data Controller for the Personal Data processing system.

**Data Controller**  
The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Site.

**Legal information**  
Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.  
This privacy policy exclusively regards this Application.

* * *

Latest update: April 21, 2013
